wvxu.org 2019-06-18

# Cincinnati Public Radio

### Privacy Policy and Terms of Use:

If you are looking to subscribe to our email lists, click here

If you are looking to unsubscribe from our email lists, click here

You have come to this page from a website or digital service produced by Cincinnati Public Radio (CPR). We recognize the importance of privacy to visitors to any CPR website, and we want you to know how we collect and use information about you when you visit our websites. This privacy policy explains what type of information is collected from you when you visit this and other CPR websites, and how we may use that information. 

**CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO PRIVACY POLICY \- EFFECTIVE DATE JUNE 30, 2018**

Welcome to the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Online Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy"). This Privacy Policy describes the information Cincinnati Public Radio, Inc. (collectively, "CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO," "we" or "us") collect or allow others to collect from you and your computer or device when you use cinradio.org or other sites, our mobile apps other applications, email newsletters, digital platforms or other interactive services provided by CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO that link to or refer to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services" or "our Services"). This Privacy Policy also explains how that information may be used and shared and the choices you have to limit or prevent certain uses or sharing of that information. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not govern websites and services of third parties that may link to or be linked to from the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services.

NOTICE TO EU RESIDENTS: Our handling of information about EU residents is governed by the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Privacy Notice for EU Residents, effective May 25, 2018. This Privacy Policy does not apply to EU residents.

By using, registering for, or otherwise accessing our Services, you agree to this Privacy Policy and CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO's Terms of Use and you give your express "opt-in" consent to the collection, use, storage, sharing, transfer, and processing of information about you and your interactions with our Services as explained in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy or CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO's Terms of Use, please do not use the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services or provide us with your contact or other information.

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us.

**CHILDREN**

CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO cares about protecting the privacy of children. If you are a parent or guardian, we encourage you to become involved in your children's online experience, and to share your knowledge and experience with your young ones. If you are under 13, please do not register for our Services or provide us with any contact or other information, including your name, postal address or email address. If you are between the ages of 13 and 18, you must obtain permission from your parent or guardian before registering for CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services or otherwise sending any contact or other information to CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO.

**INFORMATION WE AUTOMATICALLY GATHER WHEN YOU VISIT CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO WEBSITES**

We and service providers working on our behalf will collect any information that you choose to provide directly through our Services, including your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, password, age, payment card information, country of residence, communications and content preferences and your favorite Member stations. Data we may collect includes:

  * The date of the visit

  * The Internet Protocol address (IP address) of the computer or device you used to access the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services or play podcasts or other media content downloaded through our Services.
  * The domain name of your Internet Service Provider.
  * The website, application, platform or service you visited before and after visiting an CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Service.
  * Search terms you enter using the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services or on a referring website.
  * Your approximate geographic location information (derived from request header information, such as your IP address) and/or more precise information about the specific location of your device if you have given CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO explicit consent to receive this information for an CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO application on your mobile device.
  * The make, model, carrier and unique device identifier for your mobile device, the unique advertising identifier (for example, the Apple IDFA (Identifier for Advertisers) or Google Advertising ID) that allows mobile applications running on your mobile device to gather data for purposes of serving targeted advertising or personalized or "interest-based" sponsorship credits, and other information about your computer or mobile device and its browser, operating system, settings and software.
  * Automobile make (for certain connected car platforms).
  * The dates, times, duration, and frequency of your interactions with our Services.
  * Your navigation path through the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services, including any "favorites" you select, and patterns in the paths you take.
  * A list of files you download, listen to, view, email, text or otherwise share and other content preferences.
  * The amount of time spent listening to or viewing media files or pages.
  * Listening data collected both when you download and listen to podcasts or other media files. Listening data includes descriptions of the title, episodes, segments and sponsorship credits included in a podcast or other media file, time and date stamps for download and playback events (for example, when a file is downloaded and when playback of a particular segment or sponsorship credit starts, stops, is skipped or is paused), the mobile advertising identifier for your device (for example, the Apple IDFA or Google Advertising ID), session IDs and information about the device or platform used to download or play a particular file. The producers of any independently produced podcasts we distribute may also collect the same types of listening data subject to their own privacy policies, which may differ from ours.
  * Information about your interactions with our email messages, such as links you click on and whether you open or forward a message, the date and time of these interactions, and information about the computer or device you use to read emails.
  * Any errors you encountered during your use of our Services.

**ANALYTICS DATA COLLECTION**

Our Services also make use of third-party analytics, cookie data collection and linking services (collectively "Analytics Services"), including Google Universal Analytics, Google Analytics Demographics and DoubleClick for Publishers. These Analytics Services may use cookies, pixel tags, and other tracking and storage technologies to collect or receive information (not including your name or the email address you register with CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO) from our Services and elsewhere on the Internet and use that information to analyze and measure our audience and target and evaluate the effectiveness of sponsorship credits. For example, CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO and Analytics Services may use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) to inform, optimize, and serve sponsorship credits based on your past interactions with our Services and other websites or services. In addition, we may use analytics data, including but not limited to, geographic, demographic, and interest reporting information to recognize and understand user preferences, make improvements, and for other operational purposes. Each Analytics Service's ability to use and share analytics information is restricted by such Analytics Service's terms of use and privacy policy. To learn more about how Google uses data, visit www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. Information about opting out of Google Universal Analytics is included in the "Your Choices" section below.

We may track your visit to sections of our websites in order for some site features to function properly for you. In some instances, "cookies" or a similar technology may be used to update your registration records with session information. If you do not wish to accept a cookie from CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO's servers, you can adjust the settings on your browser accordingly. Refusing to accept cookies from the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO server may result in some limits on the benefits that we can automatically provide as you enjoy the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO websites.

**INFORMATION YOU GIVE US**

CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO does not collect personally identifying information from outside websites unless you choose to provide that information to us. You must be at least eighteen (18) years of age to submit any User Materials or personally-identifying information; participate in any online contests; and/or place an order on the Online Store. If you are between the ages of 13 and 18, you may browse the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services or register for email newsletters or other features of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services with the consent of your parent(s) or guardian(s), so long as you do not submit any User Materials. If you are under 13 years of age, please do not send any information about yourself, including your name, address or email address. If we discover that we have collected any personally-identifying information from a child under the age of 13, we will remove that information from our database as soon as possible.

**NAME AND CONTACT INFORMATION**

CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO may ask visitors (you) to provide certain personal information when you: register for a contest; sign up for an e-mail list; request information; purchase products or services; contribute material that may be used on the website; participate in a discussion board or chat; or use a CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO form to become a member of CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO. You will also have the opportunity to request future e-mail contact from CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO regarding its programs and websites. CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO tells you whether a specific piece of information is required at the time it is requested.

This information may be used by CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO to: verify your identity; manage CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO's members and donors; manage a contest; gather your editorial comments and feedback; contact you for additional information or administrative purposes; provide attribution for any submitted content of yours published by CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO, and fulfill your order or request. CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO will contact you only if necessary for the purposes above.

**DEMOGRAPHIC AND PROFILE INFORMATION**

CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO occasionally conducts online surveys, sometimes in association with a contest or other offer. These surveys may ask you for demographic information such as ZIP code, age, education, or income level. This information is used in an aggregate form to help us understand our audiences and improve our services. Demographic and profile information may be shared with selected third-party organizations, only on an aggregate basis, to describe the nature of our online audiences.

**COMMITMENT TO DATA SECURITY**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO has in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**CREDIT CARD INFORMATION**

You must be 18 or over to engage in money-related transactions on a CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO site. When you do so, you will be asked for a credit card number. All financial transactions take place only on secure servers, and electronic communication of credit-card information is sent only in a secured or encrypted format. Your credit card information is not saved on internal systems. This information is not made available to any third party and is considered completely confidential. The CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO website does not store credit card information for the purpose of "personalizing" the website.

**SPECIAL NOTE FOR CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO MEMBERS**

If you use CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO 's secure online form to become a member or make a contribution to CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO, your name, complete contact information, and all contributions are only accessible by employees of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Membership Department or specially-designated volunteers. Your membership information will be protected in full compliance with the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Member Lists Policy.

**MEMBER LIST SHARING POLICY**

CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO uses shared lists to maximize the benefits it can provide through other non-profit arts organizations and through qualified associations. If you are a member and allow it, your name and physical address may be exchanged for consideration with other local non-profit organizations for one-time mailing use only to promote a product or service that they offer. Such contacts from other local non-profits will only be made with CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO's consent, and CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO will only grant its consent when CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO considers the offer to be of potential interest to our members. Phone numbers, email addresses and giving histories are never shared.

CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO will not share, exchange, rent, or sell any of its lists to for-profit organizations, political parties or candidates for political office.

If you do not want your name and physical address to be used in this way, you may indicate this at the time you provide the information. If you decide after you have provided this information that you do not want CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO to share your information with any company or organization, you may also notify us by e-mailing [ memberservices@cinradio.org](mailto:memberservices@cinradio.org). CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO cannot remove your name from any third party's list; you will have to contact them directly.

The Direct Marketing Association (DMA) offers a Mail Preference Service that is designed to assist consumers in decreasing the amount of nonprofit or commercial mail they receive at home. For more information about this service, visit the DMA website at: [ www.the-dma.org](http://www.the-dma.org/) and click on "Consumer Help".

**CONTACT CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or any practices on the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO sites, please send an e-mail to us at [ webmaster@cinradio.org](mailto:webmaster@cinradio.org) or send a letter by regular mail to: Webmaster, CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO, 1223 Central Parkway, Cincinnati OH, 45214. CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO reserves the right to change this policy. Any changes to this policy will be posted to this page as soon as reasonably possible, so please check this page periodically.

**CONSENT**

Your use of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO website constitutes consent to any policy then in effect.

**WIRELESS CARRIERS AND AUTOMOBILE MANUFACTURERS**

Wireless carriers and automobile manufacturers also may collect contact and other information and precise location data from our mobile services users through processes we do not control. You should check the privacy policies of your wireless carriers and automobile manufacturers for additional information.

**SECURITY**

We employ physical, electronic, and managerial safeguards in an effort to secure the information we collect. These safeguards vary based on the sensitivity of the information. Because no security system is impenetrable, however, we cannot guarantee the security of our databases or that information you supply will never be intercepted, accessed, or disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. Because most email and mobile transmissions are not encrypted, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via email, text messages, or other mobile transmissions.

**LINKS TO AND FROM OTHER SITES AND SERVICES**

Our Services contain links to other sites, applications, platforms and services operated by third parties whose privacy policies we don't control and may differ significantly from ours. For instance, clicking or tapping on a sponsorship credit or some third-party logos on the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services will take you to an entirely different site or service that may collect, use and share information in ways that CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO would not. You also may access CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO content and the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services from a third-party site or service that may collect, use and share information in ways that CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO would not. CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of these third-party services and we recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies of any such sites or services you visit or access.

**CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO SOCIAL MEDIA**

RE: Public use of Cincinnati Public Radio Social Media sites

Cincinnati Public Radio's ( DBA as "91.7 WVXU", "90.9 WGUC" and "88.5 WMUB") presence on social media sites includes but is not limited to Facebook, Twitter, Youtube, blogs, multimedia or other user-generated sites for the viewing of a variety of content (including written, audio, video, photographs) and posting comments.

Your use of Cincinnati Public Radio Social Media Sites is acceptance of this Policy and has the same effect as if you had actually physically signed an agreement.

1\. You must be at least 18 years old to post any content on any Cincinnati Public Radio Social Media Site or submit any user materials or personally identifying information. If you are between the ages of 13 and 18, you may browse the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services or register for email newsletters or other features of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services with the consent of your parent(s) or guardian(s), so long as you do not submit any User Materials. If you are under 13 years of age, please do not send any information about yourself, including your name, address or email address. If we discover that we have collected any personally-identifying information from a child under the age of 13, we will remove that information from our database as soon as possible.

2\. As a guest posting content to any Cincinnati Public Radio Social Media Site on the internet, you agree to the following guidelines:

  * Keep the conversation civil, courteous and constructive. We encourage all viewpoints and ideas but ask that comments be respectful of others' views. No profane, offensive, harassing or inflammatory language please.
  * Honor the copyrights and trademarks of others by not posting or uploading any material that infringes on the copyright, trademark, patent, or intellectual property rights of others.
  * Do not post, upload or link to unsolicited or unauthorized advertising or promotional materials.
  * Do not post, upload or link to content that contains any product, service or political endorsements.

3\. Cincinnati Public Radio reserves the right to monitor, prohibit, restrict, block, suspend, terminate, delete, or discontinue access to any Cincinnati Public Radio Social Media Site, at any time, without notice and for any reason and in its sole discretion.

4\. By posting any content on any Cincinnati Public Radio Social Media Site, you grant to Cincinnati Public Radio the irrevocable right to reproduce, distribute, publish, display such content and the right to create derivative works from your content, edit or modify such content and use such content for any Cincinnati Public Radio purpose.

5\. Cincinnati Public Radio does not endorse any product, service, views or content displayed on the Cincinnati Public Radio Social Media site.

6\. You agree to indemnify and hold harmless Cincinnati Public Radio and its affiliates, officers, directors, employees, successors and assigns against any losses, damages, judgments, liabilities or costs or expenses (including reasonable attorneys' fees) arising out of any claim by a third party relating to any content you have posted on a Cincinnati Public Radio Social Media Site.

7\. You assume all responsibility related to the security, privacy, and confidentiality risks inherent in sending any content over the internet.

8\. This policy may be updated at any time without notice. The new policy will become effective upon posting. By continuing to post any content after such new terms are posted, you accept and agree to any and all such modifications to this Policy.

**TERMS OF USE**

Please read these Terms of Use before using wvxu.org, wmub.org, wguc.org, cinradio.org, Cincinnati Public Radio's (CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO) mobile sites and applications, any other CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO sites, applications or services, or any features of these sites, applications and services, including, but not limited to, the Online Store, Podcasts, CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO social networking features, forums and discussions (collectively, the "CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services"). By using the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services, you agree to be bound by these Terms of Use and the Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to these Terms of Use and the Privacy Policy, please exit the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services and do not use the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services or any of their features. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to modify, add or delete portions of these terms at any time by posting updated Terms of Use and/or an updated Privacy Policy on the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services. Please check these Terms of Use and the Privacy Policy frequently for updates. Any modifications, additions or deletions to these Terms of Use or the Privacy Policy shall be effective immediately upon posting. Your continued use of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services following the posting of updated Terms of Use or an updated Privacy Policy will mean that you agree to those changes.

**COMMUNITY CALENDAR SUBMISSION GUIDELINES**

The Community Calendar features arts & entertainment events in the Greater Cincinnati local community. Listings are submitted by site visitors, performing arts and cultural organizations, venues, and event organizers. All submissions will be reviewed and approved by a Cincinnati Public Radio an editor before appearing on the site. Cincinnati Public Radio, dba 90.9 WGUC and 91.7 WVXU, reserves the right to edit any submissions. Cincinnati Public Radio does not check the details of the event, and does not take responsibility for inaccurate information.

Please contact Cincinnati Public Radio if you notice inaccurate information in event listings.

When submitting events:

  * Select the proper category for the event
  * Enter the event at least 2 weeks prior to event date
  * Include your contact information
  * Fill out all information required as completely as possible.

Listings with incomplete information are less likely to be posted.

**COPYRIGHTS**

The contents of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services are protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The contents of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services are owned by or licensed to CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO or CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO's stations (91.7 WVXU, 88.5 WMUB, and 90.9 WGUC) and other producers or providers of programs or content to CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO ("Content Providers"). In the case of User Materials (as defined in the "User Materials" section below), the contents are licensed to CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO by the user.

You may not reproduce, distribute, republish, upload, transmit, display, prepare derivative works of, publicly perform, sell, transfer, assign, license or use for commercial purposes any copyrighted material on the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services without the prior written consent of CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO, except as provided below. CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO will not grant permission for use of its copyrighted material to any political parties or candidates for political office. All rights not expressly granted in these Terms of Use are reserved to CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO.

Cincinnati Public Radio will share links to its online news stories and multimedia content when asked for permission, but reserves the right to decline based on an evaluation of the request. It is Cincinnati Public Radio policy to not share or sell photographs / video to any non-partner organization. CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO will consider exceptions to this policy for non-commercial usage on a case by case basis.

Individuals may copy, download one copy on a single computer, and print a limited amount of content, for your personal, non-commercial use only, provided that (a) you include without modification all copyright and other proprietary notices contained in the content, (b) you do not modify the content, (c) you do not use the content in a manner that suggests CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO promotes or endorses your, or any third party's, causes, ideas, websites, products or services, and (d) you do not use the content in any way that is unlawful or harmful to any other person or entity. In addition, you may use widgets and tools on the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services that allow selected User Materials to appear on your personal, noncommercial website, weblog or other application, subject to the conditions in the preceding sentence.

No quotes, photographs, or other content from any material on the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services may be used in any media (commercial or non-commercial) without prior permission and attribution to Cincinnati Public Radio, WVXU, WGUC or WMUB.

**USER MATERIALS**

Through social networking features, forums and discussions in the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services, through the Contact Us page, and through other features of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services, users may post, upload, transmit and/or otherwise submit ("Submit") comments, messages, other text, photos, images, story ideas, essays, and other content and materials, and make recommendations, on or through the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services ("User Materials"). You acknowledge that User Materials may be routed through our servers, the servers of one or more third parties on our behalf, and the Internet, and may be viewed by CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO staff and on the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services by the general public. You acknowledge that the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services, the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO social networking features, forums and discussions, and other features of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Digital Services, are for public and not private communications.

**CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO MOBILE SERVICES; HIGH DATA USAGE WARNING; MOTOR VEHICLE USAGE**

CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO does not charge you for the use of its mobile sites, applications and services or any features of these sites, applications and services ("CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Mobile Services"). Please check your wireless plan, however, because your carrier's per-minute, text messaging, and data or other charges may apply. You acknowledge that streaming media can result in high data usage and may lead to excess data charges. You consent to your downloading and use of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Mobile Services notwithstanding the potentially high data usage. You must provide at your own expense the equipment and connections needed for you to use the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Mobile Services, and you agree that you are solely responsible for any costs you incur to access the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Mobile Services, including any excess data charges. You should keep in mind that the use of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Mobile Services to send content to another person via e-mail or SMS (Short Message Service) or text message may result in wireless charges to both the sender and the receiver. You agree to obey all laws related to operation of the motor vehicle during use of the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Mobile Services.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes will be posted to this page, so please check back periodically. Your use of our Services constitutes consent to the Privacy Policy then in effect. Please read CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO's Terms of Use to understand additional terms and conditions that apply to your use of our Services.

**USERS OUTSIDE THE U.S.**

Our Services are controlled and operated within the United States. Any information we collect may be transferred to, and processed, stored, and accessed by, us and our service providers in the United States and in other jurisdictions where we or our service providers operate. These jurisdictions may have data privacy laws that may not be as protective as those of your home jurisdiction, and courts and other authorities may, in certain circumstances, be entitled to access information about you subject to such data privacy laws. By using the CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Services, you agree to this transfer, processing, storage, and access of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**NOTICE TO EU RESIDENTS**

Our handling of information about EU residents is governed by the **CINCINNATI PUBLIC RADIO Privacy Notice for EU Residents**, effective May 25, 2018. This Privacy Policy does not apply to EU residents.
